[Music]
Hi guys, welcome to another episode of Four
Blogs. This is my host, Nitin. So, guy.
Bikes, and especially Royal Enfield, are an emotion
in India, where people don't buy Royal Enfields
just for their performance,
but they have an emotional value,
and that emotional value is dented when the
vehicle meets with an accident. You
can see in front of me a Royal Enfield
Hunter 350 parked there, which has been involved in an
accident. Now, after the accident,
comes the process of insurance filing, the
insurance claim. Can a
claim be rejected? What are the
ways by which
you can get insurance seamlessly? Which are the
companies from which
you will benefit? Which are the companies from which
you will benefit or suffer when the claim process comes after taking insurance? And
how can you get the best seamless experience from an insurance company? So,
today we will discuss it completely,
but before that, those who have not yet subscribed to the channel,
please subscribe to the channel. If you like the video, please like and
share.  Do it and down here on our
[sangeet]
instagram2 which is in front of you,
you can see that the
alloy suspension is bent, the chassis
is bent pipe, after that look at this, the side
box is damaged, the vehicle is also slightly damaged from the rear, I think
so there must have been damages in the chassis etc. as well and the
leg guard is completely
bent and the handle bar is also a little
crooked and these are all the things that
you can see here right now, so
look it is something like this, so now I will call
an insurance
inspection specialist who does this
work every day, whose job is that
if there is any claim on your bike, then to
file it, to intimate the insurance company
and to get all this work done, so we call
that concern person and ask him what will happen in this, so
brothers, Rohit ji has come with us,
this is an insurance specialist
who is associated with Royal Enfield, so
now Rohit ji, first of all welcome to four
blogs, hello Nitin ji, how are you, I am doing
very well, ok Rohit bhai, now
tell me one thing, the first question to you  I want to ask about
insurance, like if there is a car accident, then what is the
process of insurance filing after that, first tell
us this in a little detail,
I will not say tell me in full, but
tell me in a little detail, that means
after an accident, the person will call the RS, if the RS
is not there then how will it be obtained, tell me a little,
first of all the process we follow is that when the
car comes to us, it will either come through RC
or the customer brings it himself,
like this car, this car is completely
bent, so it is not in a condition to drive,
this is a new car, so the
company gives RC for one year, if the
customer has the knowledge, then he can bring it
through RC, that is fine, and if it is older than one year
or someone does not have RS, then they
personally tow the car and bring it away, so
what documents do you need after the car comes in, the documents that
I require include
RC, the
license of the insured vehicle at the time
of the accident, the license of the person who was driving it  It
happens and the PAN card,
Aadhar card of the owner is required, which means okay, it
means it could be that my friend is driving
but you would need my PAN card, Aadhar card, but
if the company needs it then it can be
assumed that there is no requirement, if there is
no personal requirement that you
need PUC, some companies require it,
like some government policy has been given, we
ask for it, which is with us, those from whom
our tie does not need it, okay,
now after this the car comes to you,
what happens after that, after the car comes, do
you open it completely or initially the
car will remain parked, we will not open the car until the
surveyor allows us, until we
do it, okay, that means until, okay, now tell me one thing,
like I wanted to ask one more small thing,
like right now you can see roughly above
that maybe only the chassis is damaged, now it is possible that
something else has also been damaged in the accident,
some electronic part, something,
if this happens in this case then the surveyor
tells us that we write something else in it,
what do you say,
we give all the details in the estimates  We write it down and if
we find any internal damage then we get an open
photo taken and show it
to the surveyor or he himself comes to check if there is any internal
damage then show me which one.
After this you
file the claim with the surveyor insurance company and after that they come and
check your claim properly
and after checking they give you a yes or no. If you say yes then
you start the work and if you say
no then they go
back to the customer. Okay now this is
a normal insurance process which will be cashless
so in my case we have ICICI, I have
policies from Bajaj, I have policies from Godi,
recently we have policies from IIT and Aditya
Billa Group,
Aditya Billa Group
is associated with Royal IIT, right right right,
okay now tell me that there can be
any reasons for insurance claim to get rejected
and if there are, then what are those reasons,
especially in Royal and Field. The
company can say anything about the reasons for rejection.
Anything can happen, for example, suppose the
car is in your name but someone else is driving it, there are
some companies which would need your license as well,
yes, for that, if you do
not have it, then an investigation is conducted,
in that case, if something comes out in the investigation, then the
case can be rejected, so
if I talk to you typically, then
see, I have eight cars in my house,
you all know, so in this,
most of the cars are in my
name, so if
I am driving my wife's car and an accident happens, then
in that case, your license will be applied
but in that case, hers will also be applied,
but if it is not there, if there are
some people, like
I recently bought a car in my
son's name, now that poor boy will not be able to drive till the age of 18, so
what will happen in that situation, it will be rejected, no,
if you are driving a car, then
you have a license, so it is available in that case, so
now tell me, specifically Royal
If we talk about a bike, what are the
scenarios in which claims get rejected
and for which things claims get rejected,
mostly there are chances of our claim
getting rejected, like if only
your rim is damaged, yes, an alloy wheel is
damaged, then if the company
says for that that there must have been a maintenance issue, that
you kept the air pressure low, due to this, then
your situation is bad, but tell me one thing,
if we talk technically, then how will this insurance company
prove that there was less air in our wheel,
because there is no TPMS system in it, then does the
customer not get the benefit of doubt or benefit of goodwill, it is
in the hands of the company to give goodwill, our
role in that does not remain, it will be the
insurance company, and if they reject it, then
we will definitely change it and give it, okay, so
if you talk, then
except the alloy wheel, insurance is generally given for all other things,
such a problem does
not arise, okay, now a little
tough thing  I know the question, you will try to avoid this question a little bit.
Yes, tell the customers
who are our subscribers who
watch our video, tell me
with which companies will it be easy for them to take insurance. I am
not asking that it will be difficult because it would be a
little wrong to say that it will be difficult. I am saying that
if you have a Royal A bike, then with which companies will it be
easy for you if you take insurance. Look at the claims with those with whom
we have a tie-up, it is mostly easy, it is
easy for us as well and the
customer also gets the benefit.
Well, pan India is the same type with everyone or I
mean different dealers have different deals, so it
means that from the dealership from which you are
purchasing the bike, if
you are taking insurance from there, then
please check whether that insurance
company has a tie-up with that dealership
or not. If the insurance you are taking does
not have a tie-up with that dealership, then you will have to face some problem. The
problem in the sense is that
you will have to make the payment first, the
company reimburses it to your account, yes, that is that.
This happens because of cashless insurance
and there is no other such thing and
if we assume that there is no cashless insurance, then
in how many days does the rebate come,
its time is 45 days but still the
payment comes within a week, 45 days is the
maximum
time, you have to pay it in 45 days,
after that there is
no interest, friend, there is no such interest
and Rohit ji, any special advice, any
special tip which is called
an expert tip which you
would like to give to our subscribers that if you are
taking insurance, then keep these things in mind, then it will be
beneficial, see, first of all it is better to take
zero deposit insurance, okay,
some people do not take it to save money, they get
comprehensive insurance, they are using normal or third
party insurance, then they come to me for
claim, then the claim is not made,
from where can the third party insurance come, yes it cannot be made, so
many people do not have the knowledge of this thing, so
I would like to tell these things to your viewers also, first of all
check whether you have zero deposit of the
vehicle in it.  On damage is fully covered,
okay, some companies deduct 5-10 salvage, the
rest maximum is already covered, so
get the maximum, okay, and any expert
who wants to give, that is the best, rest,
tell me one more thing, drive the vehicle safely,
what about accessories, like for example,
my Super M or Himalayan or
any bike, in that, from all accessories
to Z, what can happen in that situation, in
that situation, if you have
covered that in the insurance policy, then you will get it, so will you have to
take D on for that, you will have to
take D on, there is engine cover also
in your vehicle, like it is very important for you
because in Gurgaon, the road is
less, so many vehicles come to us
for changing the wheels etc., which then have to get the
entire engine repaired, so
those who have taken it in the insurance,
you can easily pay for that, okay, so guys, the
point is that you
must take zero depreciation, along with that you should
take engine and gear protection  And along with that,
you should also try to get an insurance for your accessories.
You have to put a lump sum amount in it. The
amount of accessories you have, so
definitely put that too. Its price is not very high, it may
increase by Rs. 500,000, but
because of that, you will get cover for your accessories as well.
Now, look at this brother's leg guard, it is
over. Now you will not get insurance cover for this leg guard. You will not get it. So,
these are small things which you
need to take special care of. And those who have alloy wheels,
pick up the stick, now we will fight as to
why they are not available for alloy wheels. Okay, so I
hope you liked this small
video on insurance.
Some of your doubts must have been cleared. So
with this note, this is me Nitin signing off
from four blogs for the day. See you
very soon in another new video. Till then,
stay tuned, stay safe, stay secure. Good bye.
[Music]